Eikaiwa Time Trial
Let's get started with Day 6 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
Let's check out a new week of Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Eigo de tsunagaru fune no tabi.
Konkai wa Scotland ga butai desu.
ということで、今週金曜日の対話カラオケでは、こんな場面で会話をしますよ。
会話相手、Conversation Partnerはこの方です。
Hello, everyone. It's Nora here.
Let's talk about something very Scottish, a kilt.
Let's learn about kilts this week and find the right size for you.
Thanks, Nora.
We'll learn about kilts.
Scotland is famous for kilts, a traditional costume.
On Friday, you will try to make a mock interview on the scene of renting a kilt.
And do you remember the theme of this month's lesson?
Dress for success in Scotland.
We are learning the theme of clothes.
Let's start with SPR training.
今回は衣類について似合う、似合わない、これらを英語で表現できるようになりましょう。
一回目の挑戦です。
Here we go!
F.P.R. Training!
では、僕の言う日本語を時間内に英語で表現してください。
濃い赤が似合いますよ。どうぞ。
答えを言います。
Dark red looks good on you.
あなたになになにが似合います。
を言いたいときに、なになに looks good on you.
では、次です。
このキルトは私に似合っていますか?
Look good on me.
を使って、どうぞ。
すごく似合っていますよ。
That looks...
軽い言ってください。
どうぞ。
この帽子はあなたに似合うかもしれません。
私は帽子が似合わないんです。
続いてこちら。
キルトをレンタルしたいのですが、どうぞ。
特別な機会のためのものですか、スペシャル・オケーションを使って、どうぞ。
アフターヌーンティーに出席します。
Now, before we move on to the next sentence, let's check this phrase.
キチンとした格好をする。英語でどうぞ。
簡単に言えますよ。答えは、ドレスアップ。
ドレスアップを使ってこの文を言ってみよう。
キチンとした格好をしなくてはいけません。
きちんとしたかっこうをしなくてはいきませんか?
きかざりすぎでしょうか?
OK, how was your first round?
Did you try to say each one?
では、ここで回答例をチェックしましょう。
Now you can check your answers with mine.
Listen closely.
濃い赤が似合いますよ。
Dark red looks good on you.
人を主語にして言うと、
You look good in dark red.
ここで洋服のことを主語にして表現しましょう。
例えばこんな疑問文。
このキルトは私に似合っていますか?
Does this kilt look good on me?
自分に似合うかどうか人に聞きたいですね。
Does 〇〇 look good on me.
さあ、次は思いっきり褒めるこのような表現です。
すごく似合っていますよ。
That looks great on you.
この帽子はあなたに似合うかもしれません。
This hat might look good on you.
私は帽子が似合うかもしれません。
I don't look good in hats.
もちろんこれは
hats don't look good on me
でも正解ですが
自分が似合わない
つまり私はを強調するなら
主語をIにしても大丈夫です。
I don't look good in hats.
キルトをレンタルしたいのですが
I'd like to rent a kilt.
Tokubetsu na kikai no tame no mono desu ka?
Is it for a special occasion?
Afternoon tea ni shusseki shimasu.
I'm going to an afternoon tea.
Kichin to shita kakko wo shinakute wa ikemasen.
We need to dress up.
キチンとした格好をするというのはwear formal clothesで通じる場合がありますが、
タクシードのようなとてもフォーマルな格好に関して使います。
ですので、dress upは広く使います。
キチンとした格好をしなくてはいけませんか?
Do we need to dress up?
着飾りすぎでしょうか?
Am I overdressed?
このam I overdressedのニュアンスは、ただ派手すぎということだけではなくて、きっちりしすぎて浮いていませんか?というニュアンスがあります。
自分がどこかパーティーに行って、きっちりしすぎて浮いている?と思ったら、am I overdressed?このように使えます。
OK, did you understand today's phrases?
それでは皆さん、今学習した表現をテンポよくもう一度言ってみましょう。
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two.
Here we go.
Koi aka ga niyaimasu yo?
Dark red looks good on you.
Kono kirito wa watashi ni niyaatte imasu ka?
Does this kilt look good on me?
すごく似合っていますよ。
That looks great on you.
この帽子はあなたに似合うかもしれません。
私は帽子が似合わないんです。
I don't look good in hats.
キルトをレンタルしたいのですが。
I'd like to rent a kilt.
特別な機会のためのものですか?
Is it for a special occasion?
アフターヌーンティーに出席します。
I'm going to an afternoon tea.
キチンとした格好をしなくてはいけません。
We need to dress up.
キチンとした格好をしなくてはいけませんか?
Do we need to dress up?
着飾りすぎでしょうか?
Am I overdressed?
Okay, time's up.
Well, how was your second try?
So, everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.